<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Casual Inferences</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Casual Inferences</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data entry form within Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/posts/data-entry-form-within-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/data-entry-form-within-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subcategories in Google Sheets</title>
      <link>/posts/subcategories-in-google-sheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/subcategories-in-google-sheets/</guid>
      <description>A problem I came across recently was how to make one drop down list based on the contents of another drop down list in order to specify categories and subcategories.
I found two ways of doing this - Method 1 is a simpler technique for when you only need one or two of these in a sheet, and Method 2 is for when you need many of these category-subcategory drop down lists as in a larger table or for data entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Covid-19</title>
      <link>/posts/visualizing-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/visualizing-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>Getting data sources</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plot google trends in R</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-plot-google-trends-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/how-to-plot-google-trends-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This post will go over some of the functionality of the gtrendsR package and showing a quick workflow of how to go from keyword to plot.
library(dplyr)library(magrittr)library(gtrendsR)library(knitr)library(ggplot2)library(patchwork)The basicsThe function gtrendsR::gtrends() is how you are able to access the google trends data. There are three elements needed to feed into this function:
the word or phrase of interest: keywordthe region of interest: geothe time period of interest: timeKeywordJust enter the search term of interest in quotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search trends during Covid-19</title>
      <link>/posts/search-trends-of-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/search-trends-of-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>The settingIt has been about a month since we have really started to feel the impact of Covid-19 in Canada. Outside of the virus itself, the preventive measures (social distancing, closures of schools, etc.), while necessary, have also impacted our daily routines and habits. Google search trends can help provide some insight into how our behaviours are changing, as a google search is often the first step one takes when wanting to purchase an item, learn how to do something, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding special characters in GGplot labels</title>
      <link>/posts/adding-special-characters-ggplot-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/adding-special-characters-ggplot-labels/</guid>
      <description>I find that I will often need to add special characters such as “µ” in my figure labels. This is an example of one solution I found to add special characters into them. The solution? Unicode characters.
Unicode is a standardized coding scheme for characters of all languages. As of March 2020, there are close to 150,000 different characters with a corresponding unicode designation. To call a unicode symbol in R, you can simply type the corresponding sequence in a quoted string such as “\u03b1” which will print α.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ottawa Winters -2019</title>
      <link>/posts/ottawa-winters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/ottawa-winters/</guid>
      <description>The settingIt was a cold and snowy beginning to Spring here in Ottawa. We had just had one of the most intense and drawn out winters, or at least that is what it felt like to me. To confirm my suspicians, I wanted to take a look back at previous years to see how this past winter ranked.
Luckily for me, there is an excellent publically available data source for historical Canadian weather data, provided by Environment Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Michael and this is my blog page that I will update on my spare time to highlight various projects and methods that I have learnt!
Don’t mind the mess, I am currently still setting things up!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>